<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Feeling Responsive</title>
		<description>»Feeling Responsive« is a responsive theme for Jekyll based on the fabulous foundation framework with beautiful typography and a bright color palette.</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The joy of foraging</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/mediaelement_js/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Food collected directly from nature appeals to me at a fundamental level. Growing up in India, with roots in the western Himalayas, I enjoyed family holidays that involved fishing or looking for wild berries. Even in the drier urban plains where we normally lived, my parents introduced us to roadside fruit like the vitamin- (and worm-) rich hard berries called ber, the sweet and tangy jamun and falsa that dyed our fingertips and tongues purple, and small wild mangoes that line some of Delhi’s older avenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adult living and working in the green and cosmopolitan university town of Oxford, I continued my occasional forays into wild foods. I picked blackberries and apples, and made English crumble. I steeped the otherwise inedible sloes in sugar and gin, and treated visiting friends and family to a delightfully scarlet, fruity tipple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet only in the past two years have I embraced the gathering of wild food as an almost daily activity. Like many others, I am uncomfortable with ultra-processed food, which is disembedded from soil, climate, culture and place. A handful of corporations control the bulk of agricultural inputs such as seeds and fertilisers, and also the global food trade. Our cheap food, produced in large volumes for high profits, emerges from battery farming, chemical dependence, pollution and the exploitation of labour in globalised value chains. The cheapening of food, and life, in the industrial food complex is symbolic of our distancing from nature. This distancing is at the heart of the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern-day hunter-gatherers or foragers that I know are part of the boomerang effect of McFoodification. In the UK, online foraging communities like Wild Food Larder (membership 210,000+) and Mushroom Spotters UK (membership 93,000+) have new people joining every day. These online groups are free, open to all, and a source of information and community-based advice. There is also an emerging foraging market, with organic retailers selling coveted foods such as wild garlic and chanterelle mushrooms at a premium. Somewhere between community-led initiatives and market-facing ones are a slew of foraging walks and courses, and foraging chefs, who also have an online presence. Here, the new or intrepid forager can get advice on what to forage and when, while dipping into hyper-local, organic produce. Hedgerow jams and jellies, elderflower or nettle cordials, blackberry gin and apple cider, ‘chicken of the woods’ mushroom pies, dandelion syrup and herbal oils are part of this new, yet old and quaint, foraging universe.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/mediaelement_js/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The joy of clutter</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//typography/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.aeonmedia.co/images/301a9ff3-d3e7-4e76-8480-c90a1d66f250/final-essay-aeon7.jpg?width=3840&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;format=auto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1990, a young Japanese photographer named Kyoichi Tsuzuki began capturing a rarely seen view of domestic life in one of the world’s most densely populated cities. Over three years, he visited hundreds of Tokyo apartments, photographing the living spaces of friends, acquaintances and strangers. These images, eventually published in Tokyo Style (1993), looked startlingly unlike the rarefied minimalism that the world had come to expect from Japan. Tsuzuki’s photos were a joyous declaration to the contrary, celebrating the vitality of living spaces filled with wall-to-wall clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th century, Japan was known for its minimalism: its Zen arts, its tidy and ordered cities, its refined foods and fashions. But Tsuzuki peeled away this façade to reveal a more complicated side to his nation. And Tokyo was the perfect setting for this exfoliation. Like the interiors he photographed, it remains visually overwhelming – even cluttered. Outside, enormous animated advertisements compete for attention against a jigsaw puzzle of metal, glass, concrete and plastic. In the sprawling residential districts that radiate from the city centre, compact homes are packed in formations as dense as transistors on a semiconductor chip, while confusing geometries of power lines spiderweb the skies above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In suburbs across the nation, homes filled to the rafters with hoarded junk are common enough to have an ironic idiom: gomi-yashiki (trash-mansions). And in areas where space is limited, cluttered residences and shops will often erupt, disgorging things onto the street in a semi-controlled jumble so ubiquitous that urban planners have a name for it: afuré-dashi (spilling-outs). This is an ecstatic, emergent complexity, born less from planning than from organic growth, from the inevitable chaos of lives being lived.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//typography/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Populous designs</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/comments/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Hornets’ Re!magine Spectrum Center project, the centre will feature over 160,000 square feet (14,864 square metres) of training, administrative, and retail space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The linear building will be composed of bands of metal panels and glass, forming horizontal lines that will be broken by wedge-shaped angled panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A dynamic swarm”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Elevated above the city streets of downtown Charlotte, the training floors are clad in a dynamic swarm of articulated metal panels – the composition highlighted by an array of sloped iridescent accent panels,” Mallie told Dezeen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We incorporated the Hornets’ coloration and branding into our design thinking, uniquely tying the architecture to the team and the city.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apt for a venue in a place nicknamed Buzz City, the bee-themed branding will continue in the main double-court gymnasium with hexagon-tiled panels between glassed offices where spectators can watch practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The space will be decked out in the Hornets’ signature teal and dark purple and is lit by a clerestory window that wraps around the space and draws light across the trussed ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty-corner to the Spectrum Center – on the corner of Caldwell and 5th Streets – the performance centre will have a public plaza on the ground floor that will filter into an atrium-like gathering space directly above it inside the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of the ground floor includes 2,500 square feet (232 square metres) of retail space that allows the public to engage with the building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/comments/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Constant confession</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/no-header/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The 2020s have seen an explosion in rhetoric about mental health – about the importance of monitoring it, tending to it, talking about it. Public discourse had already been trending steadily in this direction for years, with celebrities increasingly sharing their own struggles with mental illness, and the number of Americans using psychological services rising steadily since at least 2010. Since the COVID-19 pandemic, phrases like ‘Everybody has mental health’ and ‘It’s OK not to be OK’ have started to feel less like platitudes and more like indispensable parts of the new normal. Driven by the rise of telehealth and a massive spike in anxiety and depression since 2020, there has been an increase in demand for behavioural health services across the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2025-VW-ID.-Buzz-2-768x576.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the concept of a ‘mental health day’ has entered the popular lexicon, usually referring to a self-granted day off from work, school or other day-to-day responsibilities. This clues us in to the fact that, for significant parts of the world, ‘mental health’ is no longer simply defined in the negative – ie, as the absence of mental illness. It now also includes positive ideas about general wellbeing, emotional intelligence and self-knowledge, and a harmonious work-life balance. It is an idiom we use to understand, critique and evaluate the basic conditions of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2025-VW-ID.-Buzz-4-768x576.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools and theories of mental health professionals have also made their way into the ordinary language that we use to understand many aspects of our lives. For example, it is now common to turn to therapy-inflected language to make sense of our relationships: the concepts of trauma and toxicity have become powerful explanatory tools for interpersonal conflict. A raft of psychiatric diagnoses – OCD, bipolar, BPD and ADHD, especially – are commonly used as self-descriptors with varying degrees of seriousness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/no-header/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dutch carbon capture startup Skytree opens offices in US, Canada</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/no-header-but-image/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Dutch startup Skytree has opened a new HQ in Toronto, Canada and a new office in Nashville, Tennessee, as it looks to cash-in on attractive government incentives for direct carbon capture (DAC) technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineer-turned-entrepreneur Max Beaumont founded Skytree in 2014, following his work on DAC for the European Space Agency. Skytree’s technology is based on the carbon scrubbers used aboard the International Space Station, which remove the excess CO2 produced from the breath of astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;direct-air-capture&quot;&gt;Direct air capture&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DAC machines suck CO2 from the air like a giant vacuum. The CO2 they capture can be buried underground or mineralised into rock for construction. It can also be used to make anything from cleaner chemicals to sustainable aviation fuel for aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Skytree is among only a few companies in the world with DAC units already operating successfully in the field,” said CEO Rob van Straten. “We are eager to offer industry partners a viable, economical pathway to turn atmospheric CO2 into valuable inputs — or to store it safely and indefinitely underground.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree has built two carbon-sucking devices. One, Skytree Cumulus, produces 20kg of CO2 daily. It is targetted at small-scale applications such as vertical farming and cannabis cultivation. Farmers use the gas to boost plant growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other unit, Stratus, is much bigger. It captures up to 1000kg of CO2 per day. Skytree designed Stratus for industrial-scale applications, such as for large greenhouses and green cement plants or for burial underground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stratus units are modular, so they can be stacked together to make one, much larger machine which Skytree calls the “Stratus Hub.” The startup is planning to build one of these hubs at its base in Amsterdam. Once up and running, the company expects the machine to suck up 50,000 tonnes of CO2 per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed over more than a decade, Skytree said it has achieved level 9 on the technology readiness scale, the highest possible. This means Skytree is poised for full-scale commercial deployment, a rare thing in the budding carbon capture industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree’s first customers have largely been greenhouses. The company also recently announced plans to install a Stratus unit at the offices of Deep Sky, a fellow DAC company from Canada. Now it’s looking to scale up and into new industries including food and beverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cashing-in-on-climate-tech-funding&quot;&gt;Cashing in on climate tech funding&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree said that generous government subsidies partly drove its expansion to the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, the Biden-Harris Administration, announced plans to provide up to $1.8bn in funding to support the growth of DAC technologies. This builds on the 45Q tax credit laid out in the 2022 Inflation Reduction Act. The incentive provides up to $180 per metric ton of CO2 captured and stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The US continues to demonstrate growing demand for proven, cost-effective, scalable DAC technology driven by the needs of industry and with the backing by government,” said van Straten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree said it chose Nashville for its office partly due to its close proximity to its manufacturing partner Scanfil. The Swedish firm will make the Stratus and Cumulus machines at its factory in the nearby city of Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree said it chose Toronto for its North American HQ due to the city’s strong climate tech ecosystem and access to talent. In addition to Deep Sky, Skytree already has a partnership with Canadian vertical farming company Fieldless Farms, which uses the captured CO2 to improve the yields from its strawberry plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As part of Toronto’s passionate climate-focused tech community, I am confident that Skytree will make a meaningful impact not only here but across the globe,” said Olivia Chow, Toronto’s mayor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skytree expects to employ 80 people at its new HQ over the next three years. The company is also planning to set up its own manufacturing facility at an undisclosed site in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/no-header-but-image/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>In a State With School Vouchers For All</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-with-text/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Alma Nuñez, a longtime South Phoenix restaurant cashier with three kids, attended a community event a few years ago at which a speaker gave a presentation about Arizona’s school voucher program. She was intrigued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angelica Zavala, a West Phoenix home cleaner and mother of two, first heard of vouchers when former Gov. Doug Ducey was talking about them on the news. He was saying that the state was giving parents money that they could then spend on private school tuition or homeschooling supplies. The goal was to ensure that all students, no matter their socioeconomic background, would have access to whatever kind of education best fit them. Zavala thought: This sounds great. Maybe it will benefit my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Fabiola Velasquez, also a mother of three, was watching TV with her husband last year when she saw one of the many ads for vouchers that have blanketed media outlets across metropolitan Phoenix of late. She turned to him and asked, “Have you heard about this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working-class parents like Nuñez, Zavala and Velasquez have often said in surveys and interviews that they’re at least initially interested in school vouchers, which in Arizona are called Empowerment Scholarship Accounts. Many across the Phoenix area told ProPublica that they liked the idea of getting some financial help from the state so that they could send their children to the best, safest private schools — the kind that rich kids get to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet when it comes to lower-income families actually choosing to use vouchers here in the nation’s school choice capital, the numbers tell a very different story. A ProPublica analysis of Arizona Department of Education data for Maricopa County, where Phoenix is located, reveals that the poorer the ZIP code, the less often vouchers are being used. The richer, the more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one West Phoenix ZIP code where the median household income is $46,700 a year, for example, ProPublica estimates that only a single voucher is being used per 100 school-age children. There are about 12,000 kids in this ZIP code, with only 150 receiving vouchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, in a Paradise Valley ZIP code with a median household income of $173,000, there are an estimated 28 vouchers being used per 100 school-age children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-with-text/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Defense of the Fudd</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-logo-only/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;American gun culture expanded significantly in the aftermath of 2020. The riotous year, the most divisive since 1968, drove record gun sales. The demand for firearms hasn’t slowed in the years since, effectively sidelining the gun-control debate and creating a new generation of gun owners. While Second Amendment activists are undoubtedly pleased by the influx of new firearm owners, this expansion has led to some tension among firearm owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll start off by admitting that I am probably classified as a “Fudd.” Fudd is a derogatory term for gun owners who are primarily sportsmen, expending their shells on dove or deer while harboring a sentimental attachment to their firearms. The slight derives from Elmer Fudd, the shotgun-toting rabbit hunter immortalized by Looney Tunes. There’s some truth behind the generalization. Fudds generally carry double-barrel, over-under, or pump-action shotguns. If they’re carrying a rifle, you’ll find them with a Winchester Model 70 or Remington Model 700. You won’t generally find them covered head-to-toe in camouflage. In Texas, they might sport blue jeans and a cowboy hat. In colder climates, they might don the Elmer Fudd hat itself. A Fudd might own an AR-15 and some camo, but they would never brandish it; some might not even admit it. To a Fudd, an Armalite rifle might be a useful tool of self-defense, but it is undoubtedly a vulgar departure from the craftsmanship and tradition that once defined American sporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll concede that Fudds might be influenced by a tinge of luxury. Though I was toting a Ruger .22 and .410 shotguns when I was a small child, this is an unusual experience in an increasingly urbanized America. Access to land and wildlife, once a given in American life, is now a rarity. Despite 32 percent of Americans owning a firearm, only six percent hunted in 2023. Land accessibility—a modern privilege—is the key driver. A staggering 88 percent of the 2021–2022 white-tailed deer harvest, the U.S.’s most sought-after game, occurred on privately-held land. Fudd culture, the country’s traditional sporting culture, is becoming unattainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much to the chagrin of the M1 Garand owner at your local range, newer classes of firearm owners are crowding out the Fudds. Participation in shooting sports, generally at local ranges, increased 42 percent from 2020 to 2022. Since 2009, participation has jumped 24 percent. The change has ushered in a new, combative firearm culture. Ironically, camo sales have jumped as hunting participation has declined, anecdotally driven by newcomers at the range. (I suppose Nashville’s popification has contributed some as well.) This marks a departure from the olive green Barbour coats or khaki safari shirts that adorn your average Fudd. Second Amendment symbology, previously limited to a small NRA logo on the back of a pick-up with a gun rack, has expanded to include a collection of emblems, flags, and insignias. Punisher skulls, popularized domestically in the aftermath of the Iraq War, are a common sight at ranges across the United States. The ominous skull is generally accompanied by other militarized regalia, from tactical boots to the firearms themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever come across a Fudd, you might hear them deride the new-coming gun owners as “tacticool.” Tacticool refers to the sometimes ostentatious behavior of self-defense enthusiasts. Their ear-drums blown out at the range by AR-15s and AK-47s, Fudds are inclined to raise an eyebrow. Red-dot sights, flashlights, bump stocks, scopes, and every other James Bond–esque device you could think of strike the Fudd as unnecessary. Given the average shooting takes place at three yards, discharges three rounds, and wraps up in 3 seconds, the Fudds are generally right. Tacticools might point to hog hunting as justification for the arms race, and there’s some merit to that, but Americans have been hunting hogs since Hernando De Soto loosed them on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tension between traditional sportsmen and newcomers wouldn’t matter outside of their circles if not for the public policy implications. Tacticools, generally urban and concerned with self-defense, view their firearms as a means of protection and increasingly as a defense against government. This attitude prompted President Joe Biden to address the phenomenon, crassly blustering that domestic militias would be dispatched with the Air Force. Regardless, tacticool bravado and associated no-compromise politics create unease among the Fudds. Open-carrying an AR-15 into a Texas diner might be a legal expression of one’s rights, but to the Fudd it is undoubtedly distasteful. The sea-change in American gun culture may have provided short-term benefits, but the widespread embrace of culturally alienating habits may prove a long-term political liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fudds, despite my protests, are fading from American life. Their good-natured politics, love for craftsmanship, and appreciation for sporting tradition are as outmoded in modern America as Elmer himself. Technologists, range enthusiasts, and activists are ascendant. Just as the F-series gives way to the Cybertruck, wood gives way to aluminum alloy. A time-honored ethos is being lost, a piece of heritage American culture soon to be replaced. Activists may deride them, but a simpler age passes with the Fudd. In time, we may grow to regret their loss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-logo-only/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Putting 10,000 EVs on African roads</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-image-color/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For nearly five years, Dandao Simon, a bike-taxi driver in the port city of Cotonou, Benin, took only 30% of his daily income home — he had to spend most of his earnings on refueling and repairing his gas-powered motorbike. But in 2023, Simon heard of Spiro, a local startup that offered new electric two-wheelers in exchange for old motorcycles, without any upfront costs. The company had also set up several battery-swapping stations in Cotonou for e-bike owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon is among the more than 4,000 people who have taken up Spiro’s offer, and swapped his old motorbike for the electric Commando model. His new bike can go up to 160 kilometers per charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I love the bikes because [they have] no chain, and I’m not going to a mechanic to change the oil, so all that money going to repair is now mine,” Simon told Rest of World, as he waited to change the battery of his Spiro bike at one of the company’s more than 100 swapping stations across Cotonou. “My income is not big, but it’s doing more for my family.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019 by Africa Transformation and Industrialization Fund (ATIF), an Abu Dhabi-based investment firm, Spiro is Africa’s biggest electric two-wheeler company. The company, previously known as M Auto Electric, has so far placed over 10,000 e-bikes on roads across Benin, Togo, Rwanda, and Kenya. ATIF, which backs industrialization and environmental projects in Africa, funds Spiro and appoints its CEOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro makes money from the EV batteries in its vehicles and from the around 600 battery-swapping stations it has set up in four countries, co-CEO Jules Samain told Rest of World. The company’s success has so far been impressive, but EV experts warn it could struggle in the future due to its capital-intensive business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incurring the entire cost of vehicles to bring users into the swapping network is not feasible in the long run, Toffene Kama, principal investor at Mercy Corps Ventures, an impact-focused fund that backs e-mobility in Africa, told Rest of World. “You just take existing bikes, throw them out, and give the customer a new electric bike. But if you do that, you probably will need to compensate for that with a higher cost of energy, which can be a problem as well,” Kama said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro had initially hoped to monetize the old bikes it collected from riders by retrofitting them with EV technology — but that hasn’t worked out. Around 40% of the bikes Spiro collects are converted to scrap metal and sold for less than $20 per unit, Samain said. Rest of World visited four of the company’s branches in Togo and Benin, and saw hundreds of abandoned bikes waiting to be scrapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any bike owner can go to a Spiro exchange center, request a swap, get their credentials verified, and pick up a new EV within a week. Riders then pay a daily fee of 3,200 CFA francs ($5.32) for up to seven battery swaps, and each additional swap costs 500 CFA francs (83 cents). The daily fee also covers insurance and maintenance, and riders can take the bikes for check-ups anytime for free. After 150,000 kilometers, a rider takes full ownership of the bike and is not required to pay the daily swap fee. Spiro also runs outright sales of its Commando bike at 890,475 CFA francs ($1,470), and its Chap-Chap model at 696,631 CFA francs ($1,150).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As appealing as Spiro’s proposition is, unit economics is still the biggest threat, according to Adedotun Eyinade, energy expert and program director at the Nigeria Off-Grid Energy Market Acceleration Program, a renewable energy initiative. “How does [Spiro’s] battery-swapping stack against diesel or petrol-powered bikes especially in last-mile communities?” Eyinade told Rest of World via text. “If the recent failure of Bird Global, the e-scooter rental pioneer, is anything to go by, then this seems like another high-growth, high-loss startup, albeit serving a price-sensitive market.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro has invested more than half of the $143 million it has raised so far to reach its current scale, and it would take over $100 million to put another 10,000 bikes on the road, Samain said. “It’s a huge amount of money, to be honest. If, in each country, you want to put 10,000 bikes, you need to think about $150 million in terms of capital investment.” Samain said Spiro will continue to scrap old bikes until there’s a sustainable way to retrofit them into EVs. But that business is also not foolproof, according to Kama of Mercy Corps. “I think that some players have tried [retrofitting], but the result from our study was that the bike you are retrofitting has other problems than just the battery or the motor,” he said. “The chassis might already be broken, so you might end up fixing other things that have nothing to do with the electrification. I don’t think that that’s a viable option at the moment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, some users have started taking advantage of Spiro’s exchange offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Togo’s capital city, Lome, 28-year-old Anani Yaovi Paul purchased an old bike for cheap with the sole purpose of swapping it for a new Spiro Commando e-bike, he told Rest of World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Spiro executive, who asked to remain anonymous as he was not allowed to speak to the media, told Rest of World the company did not care much about such instances as long as the EV owners were paying their daily dues and using the battery-swapping stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro is looking to end its free exchange model, Samain said: “Now that the message is clear and everybody knows our bikes, we now think that we need to change the strategy a little bit.” The company is already testing a “discounted model strategy” in Kenya and “working with some dealers to kind of use them as a distribution line and platform to sell our bikes,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oluwatosin Osho, an investment analyst, believes Spiro’s business model has promise, and that the company could still turn a profit. “I think this kind of business model could still be fairly profitable,” he told Rest of World via text. A key driver of success for businesses using this model is their ability to raise money easier than most companies can, while rendering a service that riders can pay back over an appropriate time frame, Osho said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro has managed to get at least two governments to support its work. In 2023, it partnered with the Ugandan government to put 140,000 bikes on the roads by 2028, and with the Kenyan government to deploy 1.2 million EVs in the country. Spiro has also partnered with Chinese manufacturer Horwin to source EV bikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiro’s dependence on Chinese manufacturers could be a concern moving forward, according to Tom Courtright, energy and electric mobility consultant and research director at Africa E-Mobility Alliance, an EV advocacy group. “The problem is that [the battery market] is so dependent on China that if you have a spike in demand for batteries in your swapping system, it’s extremely difficult to respond to it in a very agile fashion, unless you have a lot of extra money on hand,” he told Rest of World. “And so, therefore, you have a bunch of extra batteries in storage. But that creates its problems because if you are just leaving batteries in storage, their state of health will get worse and worse unless you are charging them and discharging them semi-regularly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reduce dependence on its Chinese partners, in 2024, Spiro plans to set up EV assembly plants and battery manufacturing factories in the four countries where it operates, co-CEO Kaushik Burman told Rest of World over email. “We have pledged to have a manufacturing and assembly plant operating in East Africa as part of our arrival in Kenya, so this is currently being developed,” Burman said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-image-color/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>K-pop Idol Tears and International Ripples</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-full-width-image/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The ongoing scandal and discord between the powerful K-pop label Hybe and one of their artist teams, NewJeans, could potentially have a massive impact on perceptions of South Korea and Hallyu. When a K-pop star cries, the stock market mirrors the emotion as investors demand accountability. The controversy displays the hidden darker layers of the K-pop industry and the K-wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hybe, built on the success of Korean boy group BTS, has an extensive web of sublabels now extending to the United States, developing new acts like the global girl group Katseye. Yet, this music superpower was rattled by Min Heejin, sublabel Ador’s former CEO and NewJeans producer. Min, responsible for creating many of the best girl groups in the history of the industry, such as Girls Generation, Red Velvet and f(x), claimed that Belift Lab’s group ILLIT, another new group under Hybe’s umbrella, was copying NewJeans’ style and dance concepts. Hybe in turn accused Min of a host of crimes, including embezzlement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This struck Hybe’s stock price significantly as the public got wind of the unfolding argument. Shares have spiraled since Min’s statement, initially dropping more than 25 percent since the conflict began. Hybe stock recently took another serious hit when one of the members of NewJeans, Hanni, addressed the National Assembly about the labor inequalities K-pop idols encounter as independent contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanni, an Australian of Vietnamese decent, called on South Korea’s Labor Committee to better protect these artists, tearfully stating, “I know it’s not going to solve all the problems in the world, but if we just respect each other, at least there will be no problems with bullying and harassment in the workplace.” Her passionate testimony accentuated the cracks in the pristine appearance of the K-pop industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NewJeans climbed to the top of the K-pop industry incredibly fast, with their remarkable song “Ditto” recently being ranked as the 23rd best song overall of the 2020s by Paste Magazine, while the iconic critical magazine Pitchfork labeled “Super Shy” as the 13th best song of the 2020s. The group remains in the public eye as brand ambassadors for Coca Cola and Calvin Klein, grouping them alongside other notable VIPs such as BTS’s Jungkook and Blackpink’s Jennie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In as little as two years since their debut, NewJeans have attained a massive level of fame, generating huge revenues for Hybe. However, instead of introducing a new full album and embarking on a global fall tour in 2024, the group finds themselves embroiled in controversy, with Hybe facing $293 million in repayments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanni’s declaration stressed the need for change, expressing the broader global focus on social justice. The dating scandal regarding former Riize member Seunghan dives further into the nuances of K-pop idol rights and pressures they face in the industry. His overnight rise to fame became quickly overshadowed by an alleged scandal that was claimed to have occurred while he was in high school, tarnishing his public image. Seunghan’s temporary hiatus and eventual departure from Riize after death threats and funeral wreaths were sent to his label, SM Entertainment, by Korean fans, underlines the extreme lack of adequate support for idols in the K-pop industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With both the NewJeans and Riize incidents, the Korean culture of purity and submission met the global reality of the more liberalized views that most Western industrialized nations share. These negative events gained significant attention for the first time on such a scale, prompting controversial opinions from domestic and global fans and causing a divide in perception and expectation. Vilifying a member of a boy group simply because they dated in high school, or a girl group because they will not bow down to the CEO of Hybe, calls for cultural evolution within the industry to bridge the gap between domestic thought and those of the invested global audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Korean author Han Kang recently won the Nobel Prize for Literature, shocking the entire industry and country. It was a massive boon for Korean culture. Yet, if soft power is going to be a positive expression of national culture and a force for good, it must confront the inevitable internal backlash in the originating country. Koreans themselves might reject the vision the architects of culture create for them. This further highlights the growing tensions between the traditional cultural values of South Korea and the progressive views of audiences overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the K-wave rebound as a transformative source of Korean cultural power, or follow the legacy of Blackpink, the famous Korean girl group that has seemingly decamped to Los Angeles and Paris to join the global community? Will the effects of highlighting the darker side of K-pop affect its ability to project soft power? Can the Korean wave, Hallyu, remain a positive force for Korea or will it break up among the rocks of global opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-full-width-image/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Reviled to Revered, an Enormous Pigeon Perches Atop the High Line</title>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-image-pattern/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The latest sculpture to grace New York City’s High Line is a monumental tribute to an unlikely creature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perched above 10th Avenue, a hyper-realistic pigeon stops to rest in the outdoor pavilion. The work of artist Iván Argote (previously), the hand-painted, aluminum bird is titled “Dinosaur” and looms 21 feet in the air, rivaling the enormous proportions of some of its ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argote is known for questioning the role of monuments and statues, particularly as they relate to colonial histories and power imbalances. For this work, he upends the human-animal relationship and notions of migration and value as the common street bird is vaulted into a glorified figure, peering down on pedestrians and drivers. The artist says in a statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name “Dinosaur” makes reference to the sculpture’s scale and to the pigeon’s ancestors who millions of years ago dominated the globe, as we humans do today… the name also serves as a reference to the dinosaur’s extinction. Like them, one day we won’t be around anymore, but perhaps a remnant of humanity will live on—as pigeons do—in the dark corners and gaps of future worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their ubiquity throughout North American cities, pigeons aren’t native to the continent. The birds were initially brought from Europe as a barnyard animal and food source, but as they escaped into the wild, they grew into the scavenging flocks they are today. No longer domesticated and not quite wild, pigeons occupy a unique position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argote’s work is a cheeky nod to the birds and suggests they’re more deserving of appreciation than some of the figures we’ve collectively honored in the past. Standing tall and confident atop a concrete plinth, the sculpture also serves as a reminder that “everyone is an immigrant,” a statement says. “Even the pigeon, a New York fixture, initially migrated here and made the city their home, like millions of other ‘native’ New Yorkers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dinosaur” will be on view through spring. Find more from Argote on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll-feeling-responsive//design/header-image-pattern/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
